sqlbi.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy - SQLBI

## Data Controller and Owner

**SQLBI Corp.** – [info@sqlbi.com](mailto:info@sqlbi.com)  
**5348 Vegas Drive - Las Vegas, NV 89108**

This document governs the privacy notice of the following websites: 

  * www.sqlbi.com
  * www.daxpatterns.com
  * www.daxformatter.com
  * dax.guide
  * okviz.com
  * synoptic.design
  * sql.bi

Last update: _Dec 19, 2018_

## Definitions

_Non-personal data_ is information that is in no way personally identifiable.

_Personal data_ means any information relating to an identified or an identifiable natural person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

A _Visitor_ is someone who merely browses our websites. A _Subscriber_ is someone who has registered to our newsletter. A _Customer_ is someone who has registered with us to use or buy our services and products. The term _User_ is a collective identifier that refers to either a visitor, a member, or a customer.

## Your rights

When using our websites and submitting personal data to us, you may have certain rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other laws. Depending on the legal basis for processing your personal data, you may have some or all of the following rights: 

  * #### The right to be informed

You have the right to be informed about the personal data we collect from you, and how we process it.

  * #### The right of access

You have the right to get confirmation that your personal data is being processed and have the ability to access your personal data. 
  * #### The right to rectification

You have the right to have your personal data corrected if it is inaccurate or incomplete. 
  * #### The right to erasure (right to be forgotten)

You have the right to request the removal or deletion of your personal data if there is no compelling reason for us to continue processing it. 
  * #### The right to restrict processing

You have a right to ‘block' or restrict the processing of your personal data. When your personal data is restricted, we are permitted to store your data, but not to process it further. 
  * #### The right to data portability

You have the right to request and get your personal data that you provided to us and use it for your own purposes. We will provide your data to you within 30 days of your request. To request your personal data, please contact us at [info@sqlbi.com](mailto:info@sqlbi.com). 
  * #### The right to object

You have the right to object to us processing your personal data for the following reasons: 
    * Processing was based on legitimate interests or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority 
    * Direct marketing 
    * Processing for purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics 
    * Rights in relation to automated decision-making and profiling 
  * #### Automated individual decision-making and profiling

You will have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you. 
  * #### Filing a complaint with authorities

You have the right to file a complaint with supervisory authorities if your information has not been processed in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation. If the supervisory authorities fail to address your complaint properly, you may have the right to a judicial remedy. 

For details about your rights under the GDPR, read the [Regulation (EU) 2016/679.](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2016.119.01.0001.01.ENG)

## Information we collect

Generally, you control the amount and type of information that you provide to us when using our websites.

Our legal basis for collecting and processing your Personal Data when you buy our products or services is based on and the necessity for the performance of a contract or to take steps to enter into a contract. Our legal basis for collecting and processing your Personal Data when you sign up for our newsletter, workshop, services, and product information through our websites opt-in forms is based on consent.

If you do not provide us with enough Personal Data, we may not be able to provide you with all our products and services. However, you can access and use some parts of our websites without giving us your Personal Data.

### How we collect Personal Data

We collect Personal Data in different ways:

  * #### Automatically

We automatically receive information from your web browser or mobile device. This information may include the name of the website from which you entered our websites, if any, as well as the name of the website you'll visit when you leave our websites, your Internet service provider's name, your web browser type, the type of mobile device, your computer operating system, and data about your browsing activity when using our websites. We use all this information to analyze trends among our users to help improve our websites. 
  * #### When entering and using our websites

When you enter and use our websites and agree to accept cookies, some of these cookies may contain your Personal Data. 
  * #### When buying products or services

When you buying our products or services, we may collect some or all of the following information: your first and last name, email address, physical address, company name, or other payment information, phone number, user name, password, and other information listed. 

### Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of data or a text file that is downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you access certain websites. Cookies may contain text that can be read by the web server that delivered the cookie to you. The text can uniquely identifies your computer or mobile device.

Cookies can be classified in these categories:

  * #### Necessary cookies

These cookies are necessary for proper functioning of our websites, such as displaying content, logging in, validating your session, responding to your request for services, and other functions. Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of cookies. However, if you disable these cookies, you may not be able to access features on our websites correctly or at all. 
  * #### Statistics cookies

These cookies collect information about the use of our websites, such as pages visited, traffic sources, users' interests, content management, and other website measurements. 
  * #### Functional cookies

These cookies enable our websites to remember a user's choices – such as their language, user name, and other personal choices – while using the website. They can also be used to deliver services, such as letting a user make a blog post, listen to audio, or watch videos on the website. 
  * #### Marketing cookies

These cookies are usually placed and used to develop a profile of your browsing interests and serve advertisements that are related to your interests. 
  * #### Session cookies

These cookies allow our websites to link the actions of a user during a browser session. They may be used for a variety of purposes, such as remembering what a user has put in their shopping cart as they browse a website. Session cookies also permit users to be recognized as they navigate a website so that any item or page changes they make are remembered from page to page. Session cookies expire after a browser session. 
  * #### Persistent cookies

These cookies are stored on a user's device in between browser sessions, which allows the user's preferences or actions across a website (or, in some cases, across different websites) to be remembered. Persistent cookies may be used for a variety of purposes, including remembering users' choices and preferences when using a website or to target advertising to them. 

Our websites use cookies for:

  * Identifying the areas of our websites that you have visited
  * Personalizing content that you see on our websites
  * Our websites analytics
  * Remembering your preferences, settings, and login details
  * Targeted advertising and serving ads relevant to your interests
  * Allowing you to post comments
  * Allowing you to share content with social networks

By agreeing to accept our use of cookies, you are giving us, and third parties we partner with, permission to place, store, and access some or all the cookies described below on your computer.

For a complete list of each cookie used by our websites, read the Cookie Declaration section below.

### Web Beacons

We may also use a technology called web beacons to collect general information about your use of our websites and your use of special promotions or newsletters. The information we collect by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor the number of people who open our emails. Web beacons also help us to understand the behavior of our users.

## How your information is used

We use the information we receive from you to:

  * Provide our products and services you have requested or purchased from us
  * Personalize and customize our content
  * Make improvements to our website
  * Contact you with updates to our website
  * Resolve problems and disputes
  * Contact you with marketing and advertising that we believe may be of interest to you

### Communications and emails

When we communicate with you about our websites, we will use the email address you provided when you registered. We may also send you emails with promotional information about our websites or offers from us or our affiliates unless you have opted out of receiving such information. You can change your contact preferences at any time by sending us an email with your request to: [info@sqlbi.com](mailto:info@sqlbi.com)

### Sharing information with third parties

We do not sell or rent your Personal Data to third parties for marketing purposes. However, we may provide your Personal Data to third-party service providers we hire to provide services to us. These third-party service providers may include but are not limited to: payment processors (e.g. Paypal or Stripe), web analytics companies, data management services, law firms, email service providers (Sparkpost), and shipping companies (such as Amazon).

For more information on how these services use your data, visit their privacy notices at these links:

  * **Microsoft Azure** \- [Privacy Policy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement)
  * **Google Analytics** \- [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en) \- [Opt Out](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)
  * **Google Fonts** \- [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)
  * **Google Maps** \- [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)
  * **Youtube** \- [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)
  * **Vimeo** \- [Privacy Policy](https://vimeo.com/privacy/)
  * **Azure Media Services** \- [Privacy Policy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement)
  * **Sparkpost** \- [Privacy Policy](https://www.sparkpost.com/policies/privacy/)
  * **Feedburner** \- [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)
  * **Disqus** \- [Privacy Policy](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy) \- [Opt Out](https://disqus.com/data-sharing-settings/)
  * **AddThis** \- [Privacy Policy](https://www.addthis.com/privacy)
  * **CloudFlare** \- [Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/)
  * **Stripe** \- [Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy)
  * **PayPal** \- [Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)

### Legally required releases of information

We may be legally required to disclose your Personal Data if such disclosure is

  * required by subpoena, law, or other legal process 
  * necessary to assist law enforcement officials or government enforcement agencies 
  * necessary to investigate violations of or otherwise enforce our Legal Terms 
  * necessary to protect us from legal action or claims from third parties, including you and/or other users 
  * necessary to protect the legal rights, personal/real property, or personal safety of our company, users, employees, and affiliates. 

### Community discussion boards

Our website may offer the ability for users to communicate with each other through online community discussion boards or other mechanisms. We do not filter or monitor what is posted on such discussion boards. If you choose to post on these discussion boards, you should use care when exposing any Personal Data, as such information is not protected by our privacy notice nor are we liable if you choose to disclose your Personal Data through such postings. Also, Personal Data you post on our websites for publication may be available worldwide by means of the Internet. We cannot prevent the use or misuse of such information by others.

### Retaining and destroying your Personal Data

We retain information that we collect from you (including your Personal Data) only for as long as we need it for legal, business, or tax purposes. Your information may be retained in electronic form, paper form, or a combination of both. When your information is no longer needed, we will destroy, delete, or erase it.

### Updating your Personal Data

You can update your Personal Data using services found on our website. If no such services exist, you can contact us using the contact information found at the top of this notice and we will help you. However, we may keep your Personal Data as needed to enforce our agreements and to comply with any legal obligations.

### Revoking your consent for using your Personal Data

You have the right to revoke your consent for us to use your Personal Data at any time. Such an optout will not affect disclosures otherwise permitted by law including but not limited to:

  * disclosures to affiliates and business partners
  * disclosures to third-party service providers that provide certain services for our business, such as credit card processing, computer system services, shipping, data management services
  * disclosures to third parties as necessary to fulfill your requests
  * disclosures to governmental agencies or law enforcement departments, or as otherwise required to be made under applicable law
  * previously completed disclosures to third parties
  * disclosures to third parties in connection with subsequent contests or promotions you may choose to enter, or third-party offers you may choose to accept.

If you want to revoke your consent for us to use your Personal Data, send us an email with your request to [info@sqlbi.com](mailto:info@sqlbi.com)

### Protecting the privacy rights of third parties

If any postings you make on our website contain information about third parties, you must make sure you have permission to include that information in your posting. While we are not legally liable for the actions of our users, we will remove any postings about which we are notified, if such postings violate the privacy rights of others.

### Do Not Track setting

Some web browsers have settings that enable you to request that our website not track your movement within our website. Our website does not obey such settings when transmitted to and detected by our website. You can turn off tracking features and other security settings in your browser by referring to your browser's user manual.

### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites. These websites are not under our control and are not subject to our privacy notice. These websites will likely have their own privacy notices. We have no responsibility for these websites and we provide links to these websites solely for your convenience. You acknowledge that your use of and access to these websites are solely at your risk. It is your responsibility to check the privacy notices of these websites to see how they treat your Personal Data.

### Protecting children's privacy

Even though our website is not designed for use by anyone under the age of 13, we realize that a child under the age of 13 may attempt to access our website. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian and believe that your child is using our website, please contact us. Before we remove any information, we may ask for proof of identification to prevent malicious removal of account information. If we discover that a child is accessing our website, we will delete his/her information within a reasonable period of time. You acknowledge that we do not verify the age of our users nor do we have any liability to do so.

### Our email policy

You can always opt out of receiving further email correspondence from us by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our emails or by [emailing directly to us](mailto:info@sqlbi.com?subject=Unsubscribe%20me). We will not sell, rent, or trade your email address to any unaffiliated third-party without your permission except in the sale or transfer of our business.

### Our software policy

We provide several software tools that our users can download from our websites or from third-party repositories.

These tools includes Custom Visuals for Microsoft Power BI, Microsoft Office plugins and standalone application.

These tools may collect or transfer Non-Personal Data to our services for statistical purposes. No Personal Data is collected by us.

### Our security policy

We have built our websites using industry-standard security measures and authentication tools to protect the security of your Personal Data. We and the third parties who provide services for us, also maintain technical and physical safeguards to protect your Personal Data. When we collect your credit card information through our website, we will encrypt it before it travels over the Internet using industry-standard technology for conducting secure online transactions. Unfortunately, we cannot guarantee against the loss or misuse of your Personal Data or secure data transmission over the Internet because of its nature.

We strongly urge you to protect any password you may have for our websites and to not share it with anyone. You should always log out of our websites when you finish using it, especially if you are sharing or using a computer in a public place.

### Use of your credit card

You may have to provide a credit card to buy products and services from our website. We use third-party billing services and have no control over these services. We use our commercially reasonable efforts to make sure your credit card number is kept strictly confidential by using only third-party billing services that use industry-standard encryption technology to protect your credit card number from unauthorized use. However, you understand and agree that we are in no way responsible for any misuse of your credit card number.

We do not store your credit card numbers on our databases.

### Transferring Personal Data from the European Union

Personal Data that we collect from you may be stored, processed, and transferred to the United States, and possibly other countries where we or our service providers operate. The European Union has not found the United States and some other countries to have an adequate level of protection of Personal Data under Article 45 of the GDPR. Our company relies on derogations for specific situations as defined in Article 49 of the GDPR. For European Union customers and users, with your consent, your Personal Data may be transferred outside the European Union to the United States and other countries. We will use your Personal Data to provide the goods, services, and/or information you request from us to perform a contract with you or to satisfy a legitimate interest of our company in a manner that does not outweigh your freedoms and rights. Wherever we transfer, process or store your Personal Data, we will take reasonable steps to protect it. We will use the information we collect from you in accordance with our privacy notice. By using our website, services, or products, you agree to the transfers of your Personal Data described within this section.

### Changes to our privacy notice

We reserve the right to change this privacy notice at any time. If our company decides to change this privacy notice, we will post those changes on our website so that our users are always aware of what information we collect, use, and disclose. If at any time we decide to disclose or use your Personal Data in a method different from that specified at the time it was collected, we will provide advance notice by email (sent to the email address on file in your account). Otherwise we will use and disclose our users' Personal Data in agreement with the privacy notice in effect when the information was collected. In all cases, your continued use of our website, services, and products after any change to this privacy notice will constitute your acceptance of such change.

### Questions about our privacy notice

If you have any questions about our privacy notice, please contact us at [info@sqlbi.com](mailto:info@sqlbi.com)

* * *

## Cookie Declaration

We use cookies to personalise content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our websites with our social media, advertising and analytics partners who may combine it with other information that you have provided to them or that they have collected from your use of their services.

The law states that we can store cookies on your device if they are strictly necessary for the operation of the website. For all other types of cookies we need your permission.

Some cookies are placed by third party services that appear on our pages.

Your consent applies to the following domains:

  * www.sqlbi.com
  * www.daxpatterns.com
  * www.daxformatter.com
  * dax.guide
  * okviz.com
  * synoptic.design
  * sql.bi

Your current state: **Allow necessary cookies only**  
Consent all cookies \- Withdraw your consent

#### Necessary cookies

Necessary cookies help make a website usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of our websites. Our websites cannot function properly without these cookies.

Name| Provider| Purpose  
---|---|---  
_sqlbi_consent| First-party| Store cookie consent  
_sqlbi_t_lu| First-party| Store newsletter registration preference  
daxformatter-*| First-party| Store user preferences on DAX Formatter  
daxguide-*| First-party| Store user preferences on DAX Guide  
PHPSESSID, wordpress_*, wp-settings-*| First-party| Track user session  
_sqlbi_bypass_unsupported| First-party| Allow browsing website from unsupported browser  
woocommerce_*, wp_woocommerce_*| First-party| Cart and checkout  
__stripe*, country| stripe.com| Allow credit card processing  
1P_JAR, HSID, SSID, CONSENT, OTZ, APISID, SAPISID, SID, SIDCC, DV, UULE, NID| google.com| Recaptcha widget  
  
#### Functional cookies

Functional cookies enable a website to remember information that changes the way the website behaves or looks, like your preferred language or the region that you are in.

Name| Provider| Purpose  
---|---|---  
_sqlbi_iso| First-party| Store user country  
__qca, __ssid, _albexps, _uetsid, mp_*, vuid, vimeo, player, continous_play_v3, has_loggend_in, has_uploaded, is_logged_in, optimizely*| vimeo.com| Vimeo video player  
disqus_auth, disqusauths, csrftoken, session_id| disqus.com| DISQUS commenting widget  
  
#### Statistics cookies

Statistic cookies help website owners to understand how visitors interact with websites by collecting their browsing history.

Name| Provider| Purpose  
---|---|---  
_sqlbi_t_*| First-party| Track user activity  
_gid, _ga, _gat| google.com| Track user activity  
_utm*, disqus_unique| disqus.com| Track user activity  
ai_session, ai_user| microsoft.com| Track page performance  
__at*, __ut*, bt, di2, dt, loc, uid, uit, uvc, vc, ss*| addthis.com| Track user social activity  
  
#### Marketing cookies

Marketing cookies are used to track visitors across websites. The intention is to display ads that are relevant and engaging for the individual user and thereby more valuable for publishers and third party advertisers.

Name| Provider| Purpose  
---|---|---  
_No cookies in this category_
